

## Lorenzo Miret Maldonado

Software Engineer

As a junior dev, I did not know what was my field so I

decided to let them know that I was open to any task so

that I could find my comfort zone. I Started with a brand

new project that served to the company as a "proof of

concept" on the feasibility of a technology update. The

company, but the project as a whole sprung the start of

technology used did not fit the requirements of the

the update and me and 2 other colleagues were the

founders of the team that were in charge of building

from the ground up the whole base of the technology

Valencia, Valencia, Spain

🛓 22/07/1996 📓 lorenzomirt@gmail.com 📞 **622934986** 

https://lorenzomiretportfolio.netlify.app/

in lorenzo miret

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

Visual Limes Junior developer (01/07/2019 - 01/11/2021)

Biobam bioinformatics

(02/11/2021 - Present)

Software Engineer

Thanks to my experience on building and developing architectures, I had been given the task of thinking ways to build a web version of **OmicsBox** reusing the logic of the desktop version. The most challenging part of the migration was to think on the most efficient way on doing it because the company could not afford to have the whole team on it. So, for the sake of efficiency I came up with the idea of building a progressive API with the existing code and bit by bit add to the whole logic endpoints so that the web version could consume them. As of today, the state of this project is still amid of the detachment of the frontend and the backend of the desktop application, as it was tightly coupled. On this front I have 2 excellent colleagues working on it and I am in charge of the frontend of the web

https://www.biobam.com/

application.

(01/09/2015 -

01/06/2019)

https://www.visual-limes.com/en/home\_en/

**EDUCATION** 

update

Universidad Politécnica de Valencia

Computer Science

https://www.upv.es/en

**PROJECTS** 

**Portfolio** (06/12/2022 - 08/12/2022)

Portfolio made with NextJS

Portfolio to showcase my other projects and used as a use case to learn SSR with NextJS

Github issue tracker

(01/12/2022 - 12/12/2022)

Custom tool for tracking issues

Project built on the React Query course

SKILLS

**React** Proficient

React query, React 18

Spring

Knowledgeable Springboot

**INTERESTS** 

Sports

Rugby

Motorcycling

LANGUAGES

English B2

**Catalonian** Native

CERTIFICATIONS

React query

React query in-depth course

😑 ui.dev

ui.dev

React

udemy

React from 0 to hero course

https://www.udemy.com/course/react-pro/

adin (01/04/2020)

**Vaadin** Vaadin

https://vaadin.com/

AWS

Skilled

Lambda, DynamoDB, S3, Cloudfront, Cognito

CI/CD

Skilled

Github actions

Gaming

Spanish

Native

**React hooks** 

(18/12/2022)

ui.dev

(12/12/2022)

(05/01/2022)

React hooks in-depth course

😊 ui.dev

**API Rest with SpringBoot** 

(01/11/2020)

OpenWebinars

https://openwebinars.net/